MELISSA VELA CORAL Sydney, Australia.



Professional with +5 years experience as a software engineer. Able to work with agile and traditional principles across the entire software lifecycle and knowledge in programming languages such as SQL, JavaScript, C#, PHP, HTML. Highly accomplished to work in teams, learning enthusiast who always does his best to create high quality solutions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Wordpress Oriented object design C#, PHP SQL (SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle)

Functional testing and

debugging

HTML, CSS

Javascript

Git, Github

Windows/ Centos /

Redhat

Node.js and React

fundamentals

CERTIFICATIONS

ITIL V3 **Product Owner** Scrum master CPRE (Certified professional for requirements engineering)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

English, Fluent. Spanish, Native.

EXPERIENCE

Wordpress developer – Freelance, Brisbane / 2020 - 2021

- Collaborated with analysis and web design according to user needs. Customising themes to meet clients' requirements.
- Strengthened customers reliability on the website by identifying up to 6 security gaps and implementing methods such as SSL, re-captcha and restricting exposed internal users information as well as restricting access to specific areas.
- Proposed and integrated forms plugins allowing the business owners to manage their own forms including online payments.

Business analyst - TopGroup, Bogotá - Colombia / 2017

- In charge of effective communication between clients and development team.
- Improved the accuracy of the client information records and reports by 60% by designing the solution for their whole process of meat production.
- Contributed with project management duties as well as SQL sentences, testing, establishing development and deployment environments, presentations and meetings.

Business analyst - Intergrupo, Bogotá - Colombia / 2014 - 2017

- Participated in projects for 4 clients of different background, leading up to 13 people with different roles including business analysts, testers, developers and collaborated with the architecture area to take decisions according to the user needs and technical
- Proposed and leaded a solution for a 20 modules project, actively involved in decisions and validations in terms of UI Design, Requirements, development, testing and deployment, until the closing stage, validating the product with the client and achieving approvals by client stakeholders.

Software developer - Carvajal S.A.S , Bogotá - Colombia / 2014

Developed new requirements, fixed bugs, and maintained an existing software for document digitalisation using C#, Html, .NET framework and SQL Server 2012.

Project engineer - Nexura Internacional S.A, Bogotá - Colombia / 2012 - 2014

- Analysed user and technical requirements, designed solutions, proposed use cases, leaded teams of up to 13 people and validated the artefacts with the client and closed the projects in charge.
- Reduced operations costs by implementing an open source user authentication system (OpenLDAP) for the client with duties such as configuring, processing and migrating all information.
- Increased the quality of the products by planning, creating, executing test cases and reporting bugs as well as developed SQL (SQL Server 2012) to validate the information accuracy between the front-end and the database.
- Performed technical and end-user training of personnel.

EDUCATION

- Advanced Diploma of Information technology, Wells international college, 101 Sussex St, Sydney NSW 2000, Australia, 2021-2022
- **Diploma of Software development,** Wells international college, Level 5/316 Adelaide St, Brisbane City QLD 4000, Australia, 2019-2021
- Introduction to NodeJS and ExpressJS workshop 2.0 Brisbane, Dec 2017
- Leadership and management, Greystone college, Level 1&2/232 Adelaide St, Brisbane City QLD 4000, Australia, 2018-2019
- English for academic purposes, The University of Queensland, ICTE-UQ St Lucia campus, QLD 4072, Brisbane, Australia, 2017-2018
- Bachelor's degree in software engineering, Universidad del Cauca, Colombia, 2005-2012